# JUSTIN Y. CHO

### **PROFILE**

**Full Stack Software Engineer with a specialization in ReactJS, VueJS, TypeScript, and Javascript**. I am a highly skilled individual contributor with 5 years in the education technology industry and healthcare industry. My experience with managing teams and customers enables me to communicate effectively with my team, external stakeholders, and customers.

### **SKILLS**

**Programming**: ReactJS, VueJS, NextJS, TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, Express, Node, SQL, PostgreSQL, SQLAlchemy, Flask, Firebase, REST API, Redux, GIT, JEST

### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Arts at Williams College | Williamstown, MA

May 2018

Studied: Chemistry (Major), Computer Science, Psychology, Sociology, Math, Economics, Physics, English, Art, Biology, and more

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer - Smart Technologies

Jan 2022 - Present

- Part of the Lumio Studio Team, building the front-end of the Lumio online classroom product designed for teachers, frequently seen on SmartBoards in classrooms worldwide
- Designed and developed an onboarding system to replace third party service, saving company ~\$50k per year
- Designed and developed the coupon feature in the B2C purchasing flow utilizing Stripe services
- Re-architected the import code into a microservice to improve code readability and usability
- Re-designed our http interface to reduce bundle size to accelerate product loading performance
- Supported migration from Vue2 to Vue3

#### **Business Technology Consultant - Self-Employed**

May 2019 - Present

- Implemented a service to easily send SMS messages to thousands of customers leveraging Twilio API for a client
- Created custom SQL scripts for a client to support Health Quality Metrics Data Reports
- Led and taught client through a business software upgrades such as SharePoint and its features
- Created websites for small businesses

Software Implementation Project Manager - Epic Systems (Electronic Health Record aka EHR)

Sep 2018 - May 2019

- Collaborated with a team of 40 project managers on a \$20M software implementation to transition an academic hospital from its legacy EHR to Epic's integrated EHR
- Managed 5 configuration analysts to build out 4 Epic applications: surgery, anesthesia, Supply Chain Management, and medical device integrations
- Leveraged project road maps, progress reports, scrum methodology, meetings with Subject Matter Experts, and an internal task management system to ensure project deliverables met deadlines while adhering to quality standards

## **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

### tiplanner.com (NextJs, ReactJS, TypeScript, Javascript, Prisma, PostgreSQL, Vercel, Node, HTML, CSS)

**DEMO** 

- Designed and developed a trip planner tool that allows users to quickly build an itinerary and share it with others
- Utilized this project to teach myself NextJs, Typescript, and Prisma

### Jrello (PostgreSQL, Flask, ReactJS, Redux, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS)

**DEMO** 

Inspired by Trello, this is a web-based project management tool with drag and drop UX/ UI

• Developed and designed a smooth and intuitive UX with high usability by leveraging Atlassian's "react-beautiful-dnd" library so users can reorder their tasks quickly and easily

### Mr.Hood ( PostgreSQL, Flask, ReactJS, Redux, JavaScript, HTML, CSS )

**DEMO** 

Inspired by Robinhood, this is a mock stock trading platform with a simple UX / UI for beginner investors

- Integrated 2 financial data APIs with stock price data to render components and calculate a cumulative portfolio value
- Employed "Recharts" and "Moment" libraries to display beautiful data visualizations for 6 different time intervals for 10,000+ companies leading a team of 4 engineers utilizing Git version control